### **CARLA JEANPIERRE**

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly competent, adaptable, and hardworking software developer with a track record of teaching mathematics, editing written publications, and working with professionals in teams. An excellent communicator with a high aptitude for paying attention to details. Professionally trained in creative writing, coding, teaching, research, and analysis. Demonstrated proficiency in web development and engineering full stack applications.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery
- Node.js, Express.js
- Student Assessment & Evaluation
- Curriculum Development
- Media & Community Relations
- Technical and Creative Writing
- Editing

- Project Management
- Strategic Partnerships
- Academic Research

### **EDUCATION AND AWARD**

# THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY Professional Certificate in Coding, Full Stack Web Development

Washington, DC August 2020 - Present

LONG ISLAND UNIVERSITY

Master of Science in Urban Adolescent Education

Brooklyn, NY May 2015

THE NEW SCHOOL UNIVERSITY

Master of Fine Arts in Creative Writing

New York, NY May 2008

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA AT BERKELEY Bachelor of Arts in English Literature

Berkeley, CA May 2000

Institute of International Education
United States Fulbright Research Scholar

HaNoi, Vietnam 2004

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Math Instructor Silver Spring, MD
Latin American Youth Center June 2019 – Present

- Teach basic mathematics, algebra, and geometry to students who are members of the Montgomery County Conservation Corps, STEPS to Success, and MoCo Reconnect programs seeking to obtain an HSE diploma
- Utilize virtual learning platforms to deliver lessons, including Zoom, Desmos, Kahoot! and Google Classroom
- Develop curriculum in collaboration with two other educators in multiple subjects and attend regular team meetings for specialized service programs and outreach

# Academic Coach College Track at the Durant Center Suitland, MD Jan 2019 – June 2019

- Tutored and advised 69 select students from Suitland High School to help facilitate Kevin Durant's initiative to help disadvantaged youth attend college
- Taught writing and math skills to increase proficiency in regional and state standardized testing by creating daily lesson plans and developing curriculum content that target students' specific needs in accordance with Common Core State Standards
- Tracked and analyzed performance data using Schoolmax, EdReady, and PSAT practice exams.

# HSE Instructor and College Transition Coordinator Fifth Avenue Committee and LEAP, Inc.

Brooklyn, NY Jan 2014 – Aug 2018

- Provided instruction in Algebra, Algebra II, Geometry, and English language arts to adults ages 19 and older in accordance with NY State Common Core Standards and the TASC (formerly GED) exam so that students can obtain their High School Equivalency diploma; Evaluated and documented students' academic performance, classroom attendance, participation; Developed curriculum as needed in accordance with individual student needs; Administered TABE and practice TASC exams
- Taught math exclusively to construction workers at Brooklyn Woods for Brooklyn Workforce Development and to NYCHA residents as required for work training programs and OSHA certifications
- Assisted students transition from adult education program to post-secondary education and training, including preparation for CUNY assessments and the ACCUPLACER

## Writing Instructor and Workshop Facilitator New York Writers Coalition

Brooklyn, NY Aug 2011 – July 2018

- Utilized writing prompts to lead creative writing workshops throughout New York City boroughs for youth and adults
  of all ages and abilities; Assisted in the publication of chapbooks, journals, and anthologies of writing collected and
  edited in workshops
- Edited and published three children's books now available on Amazon.com

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Adjunct English Professor, Vaughn College of Aeronautics and Technology in Flushing, NY	Aug 2011 – Dec 2012
Adjunct Math Professor, CUNY College of Technology in Brooklyn, NY	Sept 2014 – Dec 2016
Adjunct English Professor, Boricua College in Brooklyn, NY	Aug 2011 – Dec 2012
Constituent Representative, US Senator Barbara Boxer in San Francisco, CA	Aug 2011 – Dec 2003

### **PUBLICATIONS**

### **Web Applications**

- https://cljeanpierre.github.io/Pandemic-Pastime/
- https://cljeanpierre.github.io/Work-Day-Scheduler/
- https://cljeanpierre.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

### **Editor of Children's Books**

- DeVerteuil, Amelia, et al., My Ancestors Told Me. New York Writer's Coalition Press: New York, NY, 2018.
- Banks, Savannah, et al., Write from Our Hearts. New York Writer's Coalition Press: New York, NY, 2017.
- Polonio, Gabrielle, et al., But Then I Grew Up. New York Writer's Coalition Press: New York, NY, 2016.